<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Andrea Piano Mortari</title>
    <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Andrea Piano Mortari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Andreapm1977.github.io/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The interplay between excess weight and hyper-glycemia on NCDs in Italy: results from a cross-sectional study</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper13/</guid>
      <description>We evaluate the prevalence of chronic comorbidities according to BMI classes and assess the interplay between excess body weight and blood glucose abnormalities in increasing the risk of major chronic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifetime costs of overweight and obesity in Italy</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper12/</guid>
      <description>We simulate BMI lifetime profile costs based on longitudinal electronic clinical data on a large representative sample of the Italian population</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stage</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/stage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/stage/</guid>
      <description>An Integrated Life-Course Approach for Person-Centred Solutions and Care for Ageing with Multi-morbidity in the European Regions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outpatient healthcare costs associated with overweight and obesity in Italy</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper11/</guid>
      <description>Data relative to 991,917 adults were analyzed. Annual per capita expenditure rose from 252.2 Euro among individuals with normal weight to 752.9 Euro among those with class 3 obesity</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing Resilient, Inclusive and Sustainable</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/grins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/grins/</guid>
      <description>Develop AMELIA, an Online Data Platform giving access to high quality data and instruments for data analysis for a wide range of applications</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obelisk</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/obelisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/obelisk/</guid>
      <description>To deliver scientific breakthroughs to enhance our understanding of the molecular mechanisms by which causative factors interact to drive (or prevent) the transition from normal weight to obesity during childhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychotropic drug purchases during the COVID-19 pandemic in Italy and their relationship with mobility restrictions</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper9/</guid>
      <description>We investigate the substantial increase in self-reported sleep disorders, anxiety and depressive symptoms during lockdown periods</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Returns to Preventing Chronic Disease in Europe and the United States</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper10/</guid>
      <description>Using the Future Elderly Model, we simulate longevity and disability over the remaining lifetime for cohorts of older Europeans and Americans</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longitools</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/longitools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/projects/longitools/</guid>
      <description>To perform econometric analysis of NCD burden due to external exposome, within a life-course approach</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring spatial effects in the presence of institutional constraints: The case of Italian Local Health Authority expenditure</title>
      <link>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Andreapm1977.github.io/papers/paper1/</guid>
      <description>We investigate the issue of measuring spatial spillovers in the presence of institutional constraints that can be geographically defined</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
